快看 出现了
見ろ! 出た!
有敌人来袭
敵襲来だ! 敵だ!
快看
見ろ!
快点
急げ!
快逃
逃げろ!
跟广岛的情况一样
広島と同じだ!
快
早くしろ!
快逃 快点
逃げろ! 早くしろ!
你们要去哪儿
Where are you going?
救命 救救我
Help! Help me!
这边
Over here!
别打了
やめろ!
快逃
逃げろ!
跑
Go!
快跑
那是B-29轰炸机 小子
That was a B-29, bub.
是逃不掉的
There's no outrunning what's coming.
矢志田
Yashida!
矢志田先生 你在干什么 快过来
矢志田貴様何をしてる? 早くしろ!
矢志田 快过来啊
矢志田 早くしろ!
你还是下来比较好
You're better off down here.
- 矢志田 - 是
- 矢志田! - はい!
这就过去...
ただいま...
我要是你就赶紧跳
I'd hurry if I were you.
快跑 马上
Run. Now!
趴下
Stay down!
不 等等 等一下
No, wait! No, no. Wait.
不要这样 不能出去 不安全
Come on, no. It's not safe.
醒醒 醒醒 快醒醒
Wake up, wake up, wake up. Wake up.
梦到什么了
Where were you?
长崎
Nagasaki.
那么久之前的事
That far back?
你在这里
You're here.
当然了
Of course.
能留下来吗
Can you stay?
你知道我不可以
You know I can't.
琴 真的很对不起
Jean, I'm so sorry.
我懂的
I know.
我再也不会伤害你或其他任何人了
I'll never hurt you or anyone ever again.
我发过誓的
I made a vow.
是神圣誓言吗
A solemn vow?
你在取笑我
You're making fun of me.
太迟了
It's too late.
不 不 琴
No! No, Jean!
不不不 不要啊
No, no, no! Please!
你是躲不掉的
You can't hide.
- 不不不 不要啊 - 你躲不掉的
- No, no, no! Please! - You can't hide!
不 琴
No, Jean!
不要
No!
大部分都配有瞄准镜
Most decorates with scope, you know.
猎物不可能逃掉
They never get away.
都记为赊账
Whack all of that on store credit.
谢啦 亲爱的
Thanks, honey.
- 买到箭了吗 - 是的
- Got the arrows? - Yeah.
没忘了买箭吧
Remember the arrows?
没忘没忘 艾迪 已经买了
Yeah, yeah, Eddie, we got them!
你在干什么
What are you doing?
天呐 你差点废了他的脚
Man, you almost blew his foot off!
你不是猎人吧
You're not a hunter, are you?
现在不是了
Not anymore.
怎么回事
What the hell?
别逼我这么做
Don't make me do this.
那个大家伙估计有12英尺高
It must have been damn near 12 feet tall.
我们一开始只听到踩断树枝的声音
We didn't hear nothing except twigs.
然后它就扑过来了
Then it just came upon us.
它抓住了莱利 把他开膛破肚
It got Riley, just gutted him.
然后又抓住艾迪
It got Eddie.
撕烂了帐篷
Ripped through the tent,
把雪地车像玩具一样撞翻了
knocked over the snowcat like it was a toy.
你就是那个被灰熊攻击的人吗
You the one was attacked by the grizzly?
我是幸存的那个
I'm the one that survived.
我想请这位先生喝杯酒
I'd like to buy this man a drink.
你叫什么名字 先生
What's your name, mister?
我叫罗根
It's Logan.
这箭头上涂了毒 据我所知这是非法的
And that's a poison broadhead, which, last I heard, was illegal.
来啊 问问我是从哪儿找到的
Go ahead, ask me where I found it.
快问啊
Ask me.
你从哪儿找到的
Where did you find it?
这个问题问得好
Well, funny you should ask.
我是从一头灰熊身上拔下来的
I pulled it out of the back of a grizzly.
射出这支箭的人
Whoever shot it,
没种继续追捕那头熊
didn't have the wind or the balls to track the animal properly...
让它痛痛快快地解脱
and put it out of its misery.
他下的毒药不足以立刻致死
Instead of dropping a lethal dose of the poison...
而是让熊痛苦发狂 最终杀死了五个人
it bled into the bear, made him crazy, killed five people.
我不知道你在说些什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
我的箭可没有浸毒
Because I don't dip my arrows in anything.
那你就没什么好担心的了
In that case, you got nothing to worry about.
见鬼
Damn.
真疼
That hurt.
抱歉了 琴
Sorry, Jean.
我要是你 就不会费力出手
I wouldn't bother with them.
即使你不出手 他们也不久于世了
Most of them will die soon anyway, without your help.
其中三个 一周后就会死在同一辆卡车里
Three of them, a week from now, in the same truck.
这把剑已经有几百年的历史了
This sword is hundreds of years old
第一位使用它的武士给它起名叫丹曾
and was named Danzan by the first samurai who used it.
丹曾在日语里是"分割"的意思
Danzan means "Separator" In Japanese.
它是分割头颅与四肢的理想武器
The ideal weapon for separating head and limb from body.
就像这样
Like so.
我的车停在后巷
I'm parked in back.
上车
Get in.
见谅 这车是租来的
Sorry, it's a rental.
你是谁
Who are you?
我吗 我叫雪生
Me? I'm Yukio.
然后呢
And?
我试图找你有一年多了
I've been trying to find you for over a year.
为什么
Why?
把那个给你
To give you that.
我的雇主希望你能收下
My employer wanted you to have it.
你的雇主是谁
Who's your employer?
矢志田大人
Master Yashida.
他说那是你的东西 他要把欠下的债都还清
He said it belongs to you, and that he's paying all debts.
矢志田大人快要死了
Master Yashida is dying.
他想对你说声谢谢 感谢你多年前救了他
He wants to say thank you for saving his life all those years ago.
他知道你是个...
He knows that you are a...
大忙人
busy man.
但他真的很想亲自和你告别
But he very much wants to say his goodbye in person.
好吧 他在哪儿
All right, where is he?
东京
Tokyo.
等等 我才不去日本
Wait...I'm not going to Japan.
连临终之人的请求都拒绝 太不近人情了吧
It would be dishonorable for you to refuse his request.
那还真是对不起矢志田先生了 我不会去东京的
Well, apologize to Mr. Yashida, I'm not going to Tokyo.
明白吗 我还有事要办
All right? I've got things to do.
不用道歉
Do not apologize.
能见到金刚狼已是我莫大的荣幸了
It's been an honor just to meet the Wolverine.
我已经不是金刚狼了 明白吗
That's not who I am anymore, you understand?
有意思
Interesting.
如果你不是为了伸张正义 为何去那家酒吧
Why did you go into that bar, if not to seek justice?
- 我不知道 - 你不知道吗
- I don't know. - You don't know?
- 没错 - 我觉得你知道
- No! - I think you know.
- 停车 - 你是一名战士
- Pull over. - You are a soldier.
不 我不是 停车
No, I'm not. Pull over.
你就是一名战士
You are a soldier.
立刻停车
Pull over, now!
立刻
Now.
你骨子里是名战士
You are a soldier,
你跟所有战士都有着同样的追求
and you seek what all soldiers do.
追求什么
And what's that?
体面的死亡
An honorable death.
痛苦的终结
An end to your pain.
谁说我处于痛苦之中的
Who says I'm in pain?
夜夜做噩梦的人怎么会不痛苦
A man who has nightmares every night of his life is in pain.
一天时间
One day.
和矢志田先生告别后 我就立马回来
I say goodbye to Mr. Yashida and I come right back.
没问题
Okay.
15个小时的航程 取决于风向和风速
Fifteen hours. Depending on the wind.
15个小时
Fifteen hours?
你不喜欢飞行吗
You don't like to fly?
我爱死了
I love it.
狼獾
Kuzuri?
Kuzuri.
狼獾
“狼獾”是什么意思
Kuzuri. What does that mean?
怪物
Monster.
不疼吗
No pain?
- 你感觉不到... - 当然疼
- You have no... - Oh, yeah. Pain.
非常痛苦
Plenty of pain.
你活多久了
How old are you?
很久很久了
It's been a long time.
经历了很多战争
Many wars.
明白吗
Understand?
太多该死的战争了
Too many fuckin' wars.
就快到了
We are almost there.
你能预见未来
So, you can see the future?
我会看地图
I can read a map.
你说你知道酒吧里那些混蛋的未来
You said you knew the future of those assholes in the bar.
我知道他们会死
I know they are going to die.
我们都会死
We are all going to die.
你说他们一周后会死在同一辆卡车里
You said they would die in the same truck, in a week.
如果应验了的话 那真是了不起的超能力
If you're right, that's quite a talent.
不是所有人的超能力都是爪子
We don't all have claws.
那我会死在这架飞机上吗
So, do I die on this plane?
不会
No.
至少不是这架
Not on this plane.
别被这些灯光蒙蔽
Don't let the lights fool you.
日本还处于黑暗中
These are dark days in Japan.
有人认为一旦矢志田大人病倒
Some believe when Master Yashida got sick,
日本便会蒙上阴影
a shadow fell upon us.
你也觉得他是神吗
Do you think he's a god?
不 他只是个人 不过是个伟人
No. A man. But a great one.
战后 他帮助日本重建
After the war, he helped rebuild the nation.
他的家族企业也成为日本最大的企业
And the family business became Japan's largest.
他们把这些做成卡片让你们背诵了吧
Did they give you a little card to memorize?
我的命是矢志田大人救的
I owe Master Yashida my life.
别犯浑
Don't be a dick.
这么多枪
A lot of guns.
因为最近遇到了几次袭击
There have been attacks.
绑架未遂 刺杀未遂
Attempted kidnappings. Attempted assassinations.
谁指使的
By Who?
日本的黑帮 山口组
The Japanese mob, the Yakuza.
政府越来越弱 他们却发展壮大
They've grown strong as the government has grown weak.
有武器反应
武器の反応あり
他没问题
大丈夫だから
把你的武器拿出来
武器を見せてください
我不是说了他没问题吗
大丈夫だって言ってるでしょ?
我做过髋关节置换手术
Hip replacement.
请换上
どうぞ　お履きください
太小了
Uh, too small.
Too small.
这边请
This way.
那是谁
Who's that?
信玄 矢志田大人的儿子
Shingen, Master Yashida's son.
他挺厉害
He's good.
他也就还行吧
He's all right.
好久不见
お久しぶりです
为什么不让穿靴子
So, what happened to the badass in boots?
矢志田大人是个传统的人
Master Yashida is traditional.
既怀念过去 又紧盯未来
One eye on the past and the other on the future.
爷爷 您还活着 我不要
生きたから　そんなお爺様
这必须由你来做
お前でなければできない
那是真理子 他的孙女
That's Mariko, his granddaughter.
真理子
Mariko.
怎么了 发生什么事了
どうした?　何があったの?
没事
大丈夫　なんでもない
你最近都没有回我邮件
メールだって最近全然返事がないし
现在不能告诉你
今は説明できない
为什么 你跟我说清楚啊
どうして　ちゃんと言ってよ
那个脏兮兮的人是谁
あの汚い人は誰?
是你爷爷让我找的人
あの方は矢志田様が捜してと言ってた人
你不能让他这样子见爷爷
あんな汚い格好でお爺様に会わせないで
静和沙纪会为你消毒
Shizu and Saki are going to disinfect you.
帮你修剪毛发
Give you a shave.
她们敢动我试试看
Like hell they are.
到浴缸里去
Get in the tub.
不是吧
Really?
- 坐好 - 坐好
- 座りなさい　- 座りなさい
- 坐好 - 好的
- 座りなさい - All right.
- 坐好 - 你不要动了
- 座りなさい　- もう動かないで　ちょっと
怎么了 舒服吧
なに　気持ちいいでしょ
你别动
このままにしてなさい
好了 好吧
Okay. Okay.
好了 好了 这个我自己来
All right, all right, all right. I can do that bit.
怎么了
What?
你看上去很帅
You look nice.
我觉得被侵犯了
I feel violated.
为矢志田大人再准备两瓶抑制剂
Prepare two more suppressors for Master Yashida.
然后测一下他的血压
And check his blood pressure.
矢志田大人
Yashida-sama.
我完成您交代的任务了
ご用命通りに
狼獾
Kuzuri.
你还是老样子啊
You look the same.
不过这也没什么奇怪的
But, then, that is no surprise.
格林医生
Dr. Green.
请你先退下吧
Leave us, please.
最多5分钟
Five minutes, no more.
她是我的肿瘤治疗专家
My oncologist.
不错啊
Well done.
不用了 雪生 这种预防措施对我已经没用了
Oh, forget that, Yukio. I'm past such precautions.
多年来 我一直想感谢你的救命之恩
For many years I have wanted to thank you for saving my life.
你当年对我也大发善心
You were kind to me.
你对很多人都很友善
And you were kind to many people.
我在那个深井里甚至都看出来了
I saw that even from that well.
画上画的是我出生的村庄
The painting is from the village of my birth.
描绘出了黑衣族的勇猛和高超技艺
It depicts the bravery and skill of the Black Clan.
忍者武士
Ninja warriors.
他们已经守护我们家族七个世纪了
They served my family for seven centuries.
我找你来并非只是想感谢你 罗根
I didn't send for you only to thank you, Logan.
我想要报答你
I wanted to repay you.
给你一些别人都给不了的东西
To offer you something no one else can.
一份可以报答救命之恩的礼物
A gift to equal the life you gave to me.
我什么都不需要
I don't need anything.
并非一件物品
Not a thing.
永生是种诅咒
Eternity can be a curse.
对你来说 没有尽头的生命并不容易
It hasn't been easy for you, living without time.
你要承受很多失去的痛苦
The losses you have had to suffer.
人可能会失去活着的意义
A man can run out of things to live for.
失去人生目标
Lose his purpose.
成为一个浪人
Become a ronin.
一个无主的武士
A samurai without a master.
我可以帮你终结这种永生
I can end your eternity.
帮你成为凡人
Make you mortal.
他们对我所做的 现在这样的我
What they did to me, what I am,
是无法逆转的
can't be undone.
矢志田工业是无所不能的
Yashida Industries can do anything.
我们有理由相信你的愈合能力是可以转移的
We have reason to believe your ability to heal can be passed.
转移
Passed?
从你身上转移到别人身上
From you to another.
你已经挣扎了太久 罗根
You have struggled long enough, Logan.
我糊涂了
I'm confused.
我来这里只是为了跟故交告别
I came here to say goodbye to a man I once knew.
我的想法没有变
I am the same man.
当年我还没有准备好赴死
I was not ready to die then.
现在还是没有准备好
I am not ready to die now.
但你已经准备好了
But you are...
不是吗
aren't you?
- 你这是提出要杀了我 - 不
- Are you offering to kill me? - No.
不是让你马上死
Not right away.
你可以过完你悠长平凡的一生
You can live a long and ordinary life.
恋爱 成家
Fll in love, have a family,
慢慢变老
grow old.
然后有一天 正常死亡
And one day, die an ordinary death.
这是可以做到的
It can be done.
好吧 够了 再次见到你很高兴
Yeah, look, nice to see you again.
我很遗憾你病了
Sorry you got sick.
拜托了 罗根先生
Please, Logan-san.
我需要你再次相助
I need you again.
我担心我的家人
I fear for my family.
我担心我亲手建立的一切
I fear for everything I have built.
- 时间到了 - 求你了
- Enough. - Please.
- 求你了 罗根先生 - 你该走了
- Please, Logan-san. - You should leave.
他们会杀了她
They're going to kill her.
谁
Who?
真理子 我孙女
Mariko, my granddaughter.
她是我的掌上明珠 一定要保护好她
She is my treasure. She must be protected.
你不会想要我的超能力的
You don't want what I've got.
狼獾
Kuzuri.
Kuzuri?
信玄大人 您父亲在找您
信玄様　お父様がお呼びでございます
终于等到这个时候了吗
時が来たか
父亲 父亲
お父様　お父様
- 小姐 您请回吧 - 让开
- お嬢様　どうぞお引きください　- どいてよ
- 您不能进去 - 你让我进去 父亲
- ご入室できません　- ちょっと通して　お父様
您不能进去 真理子小姐
ご入室できません　真理子様
在我父亲去找爷爷前 我要和他谈谈
お爺様にお会いになられる前に　お話があるの
让开 父亲
どいてよ　お父様
您看这要怎么办
どう致しましょうか
他一会儿会和你谈 真理子
信玄様は　明日の朝　お話になりたいと
父亲 我现在就要和你谈
今じゃなきゃダメなの　お父様
现在不行 真理子
今はならん　真理子
- 求您了 父亲 - 你快离开
- お願いです　お父様　- 離れなさい
等等 父亲 您听我说
待ってくださいお父様　話を聞いて下さい
我不是说了现在不行吗 真理子
今はならんと言ってるんだ　真理子
- 求您了 父亲 - 以后再说
- お願いです　お父様　- 後にしなさい！
您听我说
話を聞いて下さい
我父亲现在都快断气了
私の父が息を引き取ろうとしている
所以您现在才要听我说清楚
だからこそ今聞いていただかなきゃならないだよ
你不要挡着我 快点离开
ここをどきなさい
你总是这样
君はいつだってそうだよ
所以爷爷才会那么难过
だからお爺様が悲しむんだ
真理子小姐
真理子様
小心 小心 这里很滑
Careful, careful. It's slippery out here.
放开我
Let go.
你闹够了吗
You about done?
放开我
Let go of me.
你不是说他只是想和我告别吗
He just wanted to say goodbye, huh?
你们两个一起长大的
You two grew up together.
是的
Yes.
但你并不是她的妹妹
But you're not her sister.
没错
No.
矢志田大人在去南方时发现了我
Master Yashida found me on a trip to the South.
他带真理子去参观一个他正在建设的工厂
He brought Mariko to see a factory he was building.
我当时正在垃圾堆里翻找食物
I was digging through the garbage for something to eat.
所以他们就带你回来了
So they just took you home with them?
真理子一直很难交到朋友
It was always difficult for Mariko to make friends.
我会安排飞机明天一早起飞
I'll see to it the plane is ready in the morning.
先睡这儿吧
Sleep here.
你别一脸失望的样子啊 信玄
そんなにがっかりした顔するなよ　信玄
我还没死透呢
私はまだ死んじゃいない
需要我的话 就去办公室找我
I'll be in my office if you need me.
接下来的话很难开口
これを言うのは容易いことではないが
不过我们之间对话从来都很困难 不是吗
我ら親子の間には容易いことなどなに一つなかったな
我努力过了 爸爸
謹んで務めてまいりました
你已经尽力了
お前は最善を尽くしたのだろう
你一直是我认定的继承者
You have always been my assumed successor.
过去的几年 作为考验
So the past few years, as a test,
我让你握有更多的控制权
I allowed you more control.
我很荣幸
It has been an honor.
但我现在意识到 那是个错误
And I now realize that was a mistake.
你把公司推向了毁灭的边缘
You have brought this company close to ruin.
我死后 会有其他人代替我成为总裁
When I die, someone else will take my place as chairman.
父亲 如果让您失望了 我很抱歉
Father, I'm sorry if I have disappointed you...
就别说些假话来侮辱彼此了
Let's not insult one another.
你不会成为矢志田家族的领导者
You are not the man to lead Yashida.
您不能让外人来当领导
You cannot bring in someone from the outside.
这一点 你说得没错
In that, you are correct.
我绝对不允许这种事情发生
そんなことは絶対に許されない
永生是种诅咒
Eternity can be a curse
狼獾
Kuzuri.
你感觉不到疼痛吗 狼獾
You have no pain, Kuzuri?
你活多久了
How old are you?
真是个有趣的提议
Interesting offer.
为什么要拒绝那个老人
What are you doing turning the old man down?
我以为你想和我在一起
I thought you wanted to be with me.
过来
Come here.
他去世了
He's dead.
我没预见到会这样
I didn't foresee it.
您对从您的父辈开始
お父上の時代から　最大の立会者であり
最大的立会人矢志田一郎先生的死有什么看法呢
うじの男性だった矢志田一郎さんの死についてどう思われますか
应该怎么说呢
なんと申し上げれるか
和真理子在一起的是谁
Who's that? With Mariko.
他叫森信郎
His name is Noburo Mori.
司法部长 政界新星
Minister of Justice, a rising star.
真理子的未婚夫
He's Mariko's fiance.
你得鞠躬
You need to bow.
鞠躬
Bow.
信玄大人 这位是罗根先生
Lord Shingen, this is Mr. Logan.
我知道他是谁
I know who he is.
你父亲是个好人
Your father was a good man.
他也是这么说你的
He would often say the same about you.
不过话又说回来 他一直痴迷于你们这种人
But then, he was always fascinated with your kind.
告诉我 你觉得他为什么让雪生去找你
Tell me, why do you think he sent our little Yukio to fetch you?
来告别
To say goodbye.
那既然已经告别了
And now you have.
你也该打道回府了
Time for you to go back to your cave.
你还希望我见见什么人吗
Anyone else you want me to meet?
我向您起誓
私は誓います
矢志田大人
矢志田様
我将保持警惕
警戒を怠らず
不惜性命
真理子を守ることに
保护真理子
人生を捧げると
那是白银武士的盔甲
That armor belonged to Shiruba-Samurai
也就是银武士
the Silver Samurai.
它将永远守护着它的主人
It will stand watch over the old man forever.
罗根
Logan?
有什么地方不对劲
Something's not right.
放开我
Let go.
能请您退下吗
下がっていただけますか
快退下
下がりなさい
退下
下がれ
快退下
さがりなさい
退下
下がれ
快退下
さがりなさい
退下
下がれ
罗根
Logan!
放开我
放して
罗根
Logan!
你拍什么拍 快给我关了
ビデオ撮ってんじゃねえぞこら　止めろこら
投降吧 外国佬
伏せろ　外人
快把她带走
連れて行ってください
上
行くぞ
投降吧 外国佬
伏せろ　外人
你以为你能逃得掉吗
逃げられるですか
上
行け
狼獾
Kuzuri.
我们走 快跑
Let's go. Come on, let's go!
- 雪生 - 真理子
- Yukio! - Mariko!
你要去哪
どこへ行く
快逃
行け
真理子
Mariko!
别跑
逃げるな
站住
待って
上
行くぞ
快上
ほら行くぞ
快 快跑
Come on. Let's go, let's go.
站住
待ちなさい
你小子干什么呢
何やってんだ
到这边来
Here, here! Here!
站住
止まれ
这里 过来
In here! Move!
我杀了你 死外国佬
殺すぞ　こら　外人
我不会放过你的
逃がさんぞ
快跑 继续跑
Keep moving, keep moving.
跑啊
Move!
你在流血 你需要救治
You're bleeding. You need help.
先跑吧
Just keep moving.
谢谢你刚刚所做的一切
Thank you for what you did back there.
- 那些是山口组的人 - 我没事
- Those were Yakuza. - I'm fine.
他们为什么追杀你
Why are they after you?
我没事 从这里开始我自己走
I'm fine. I can make my way from here.
你该走了 去找个医生
You should go. Get yourself a doctor.
真舒服
That's nice.
这是新干线列车对吗
This is one of those bullet trains, right?
我说了我不需要你的帮助
I told you I don't need your help.
它能跑多快 每小时300英里吗
So what do they do, like, 300 miles an hour?
麻烦您说一句
お願いします
这次卑鄙的袭击
今回の卑劣極まりない厚かましいとしか言えぬ犯行は
是暴力团伙那帮人所为
暴力団の仕業であります
我曾经粉碎过他们的犯罪计划
組織犯罪の取り締まりを強化した
所以这就应该是他们的暴力反抗行为
我々に対する暴力的な反応だと言えるでしょ
有人看到他们从北门出去了
目撃者によると北門から出ていたそうです
她跟那个奇怪的外国人在一起
あの　不思議な外人に連れ添われ
你的那位外国朋友在哪儿
Your gaijin friend, where is he?
最后一次看到他时 他在保护您的女儿
Last I saw, he was protecting your daughter.
你不过是个玩偶
You are a toy doll.
陪伴小孩子的玩具 她长大了 不再需要你了
A companion for a child who has outgrown you.
你最好记住这一点
Keep that in mind.
佳世 你没事吧
佳世　大丈夫か
这是要去哪儿 真理子
So, where are we headed, Mariko?
我们要去哪里
Where are we going?
我会在终点下车
I'm going to the end of the line.
我们家在南边有座房子
My family has a home in the South.
这太蠢了
That's stupid.
无意冒犯 但他们肯定知道去那里找你
No offense, but they're gonna know to look for you there.
那个地方他们不知道
Not this place.
- 你不希望被打扰 - 没错
- You want to be left alone. - Yes.
- 我理解 - 真的吗
- I understand. - Do you?
是的 相信我
Oh, yeah. Trust me.
问题是 我若真离开了
Problem is, if I do that
你怕是连一天都活不过
I don't think you're gonna live to see the end of the day.
坏事发生时 你不能假装它没发生 小公主
You can't pretend shit isn't happening when it is, princess.
除非你想寻死
Unless you want to die.
那样的话 你这样胡闹倒是没什么
in that case, you are playing this perfectly.
什么鬼情况
What the hell?
我这是怎么了
What the hell is happening?
是那个外国佬
あの外人だ
就是那个外国佬
开枪
撃て
撃つぞ
干掉他
やっちまえ
你这是怎么了
What happened to you?
快下车 快
We get off here. Let's go.
听我说 我们得找个安全的地方
Just listen to me, will you? We need to find someplace safe.
我不明白
I don't understand.
你怎么知道他们是山口组的
How do you know they were Yakuza?
他们和庙里的袭击者是同一伙的
They were the same guys from the temple.
你怎么知道他们在追杀我
How do you know they were after me?
听着 我们要找个安全的地方
Look, we need to find someplace safe.
不能待在大街上
We need to get off the streets.
- 我不明白 - 闭嘴 听好了
- I don't understand. - Shut up! Listen.
你熟悉这地方吗 市区在哪里
Do you know this place? Where's downtown?
直走
Straight ahead.
那闹市区在哪儿
So, where's the nice part of town?
往那边走八个街区
Another eight blocks that way.
好 我们就待在这里
Good. We're staying here.
我们走
Let's go.
这是家情侣宾馆
This is a love hotel.
什么宾馆
A what?
情侣宾馆
A love hotel.
专为情侣服务的 懂了吗
For couples, understand?
好吧
Right.
要两个房间 相邻的 同一层的
Two rooms. Adjoining rooms, on the same floor.
我听不懂英语
英語話せない
- 要相邻的 - 我听不懂英语
- Right next to each other. - 英語話せない
紧挨着的那种
Very close.
不懂 英语 不懂 英语 不懂
ノー　英語　ノー　英語　ノー
- 听不懂英语 - 同一层 同一层
- 英語　ノー - Same floor. Same floor.
英语 不懂 英语 不懂不懂不懂
ノー　英語　英語ノーノーノー
我们想要两个房间
あの　二部屋お願いしたいんですけど
有相邻的房间吗
隣同士になってるとこありますか
现在人很多
今混んでるからね
现在空着的房间
空いてんのはね
就只有地牢房 护士房
地下の牢屋　ナースの部屋
还有火星探险房了
火星探検
她说什么
What did she say?
她说没有相邻的房间了
She has no rooms available next to each other.
她问我们要地牢房 护士房
She's asking if we prefer "The dungeon", "The nurse's office",
还是火星探险房
or the "Mission to Mars."
这倒也可以
This'll do.
发射 即将发射
Liftoff! We have a liftoff!
其实还挺温馨
Kind of homey, actually.
你打算睡哪儿
Where do you plan on sleeping?
我不睡
I don't.
你流了好多血
That's a lot of blood.
我以为你不再当英雄了
I thought you were done being the hero.
但那些人打算杀了她
But these guys were trying to kill her.
放弃吧
Just let it go.
死亡并非难事
It's not hard to die.
来我这儿吧
Come to me.
罗根
Logan
你走神了
You're slipping.
你给我站住 你逃不掉的
待ってこら　逃げるんかい
你小子怎么回事
なんやお前
干掉他
やれ　こら
罗根
Logan
你小子死定了
見てんだい　こら
临死前想说什么吗 外国佬
Wanna say something before you die, gaijin?
怎么了 发生什么事情了
なんや　何が起きたや
是谁
誰や
他被干掉了
やられたか
(好梦酒店)
我是担心才这么说的
心配だから言ってるでしょ
后面就交给我了
後俺やるから
不行 我担心 不行
ダメ　心配　ダメ
- 后面的我来就行了 - 不行 我还是担心
- 俺やってやるから　- 心配だから
他醒了
起きました
这是旅馆老板美惠和她的孙子仁志
This is Mieko from the hotel and her grandson, Hitoshi.
他是医生吗
Is he a doctor?
也算是吧
In a manner of speaking, yes.
他是个兽医
He's a veterinarian
还是学生
student.
研究大型动物
Large animal.
谢谢你
Thanks.
他给你缝合时 你好像划了他几下
You may have cut him once or twice while he was stitching you.
好了 没事了 没事了
Okay, okay, okay.
这些我来收拾就好了
もう　私方付けて置くんで
你们去休息一下吧
少しお休みになってください
好 我知道了
分かりました
谢谢你
Thank you.
我以前从不需要这些
I never needed this before.
什么 帮助吗
What? Help?
救治你爷爷的那个医生 金发的那个
That doctor, the one who helped your grandfather, the blonde.
她是谁
Who is she?
她是爷爷去年去美国治疗时遇到的
He met her last year when he was in America for treatment.
你爷爷说我的自愈能力可以被夺走
Your grandfather told me my healing could be taken from me,
传给别人
passed on.
我这次没有像以前一样自愈
I'm not getting better, not like before.
是她干的
She did this to me.
金发妞
Blondie!
金发小姐姐 等一下
金髪の姉ちゃん　待ってって
金发妞 等一下
Blondie!　待て待て待て
看这边嘛
こち向けって
真漂亮
いいね
开个价 开个价 开个价吧
How much? How much, yeah? How much?
我等了你两个小时 你一点都不尊重我
You kept me waiting two hours. You have no respect.
所以你还没找到他们吗
So you haven't found them?
别耍我 贱人 小心我杀了你
Don't play with me, bitch. I could kill you.
如果你真能让我有任何感觉 原田
If you could make me feel something, Harada,
那简直太好了
that would be sublime.
我可以把你这张漂亮的嘴划开
I can slit your pretty mouth open,
免得你说出什么蠢...
before you open it to say one more stupid...
我只要你做一件事 小矮人
I asked you to do one thing, little man.
把那个变种人带来给我
Bring me the mutant.
我并不效力于你 我是为...
I don't work for you. I work for the House of...
你为矢志田效力 我明白
You work for Yashida, I get it.
但你却无法完成他的遗愿
Yet you cannot fulfill his dying wish.
天啊 你知道你让他有多失望吗
My God, if you had any idea how much you have failed him.
罗根在哪儿 我还没处理完他呢
Where is Logan? I am not done with him.
那个变种人有超能力
The mutant has powers.
他现在不过是凡人之躯 肉体十分脆弱
He's just a man now. His flesh is weak now.
是我干的
I did that.
我抑制了他的力量 好让他容易被抓到
I suppressed his power so he could be taken.
所以 你应该尊重我才对
You see, it's me you should respect.
赶在山口组之前找到他们
Just find them, before the Yakuza.
该下车了
We get off here.
这是哪里
Where are we?
就在长崎的外围
Just outside Nagasaki.
这边走
This way.
这是葬礼上的那个弓箭手
This is the guy from the funeral, the archer.
他是你前男友
He was your boyfriend.
他叫原田
That's Harada.
那年夏天我们成了村里的冠军
We were village champions that summer.
他是射箭冠军 我是飞刀冠军
He with the bow and me with the knives.
原田和我本打算结婚的
Harada and I were planning to get married.
被谁阻止了
What stopped you?
爷爷
Grandfather.
他说我们必须等到至少15岁才能结婚
He said we had to wait until we were at least 15.
这里有山珍 也有海味
From the mountain, from the sea.
开动咯
いただきます
开动
把筷子竖着插是不吉利的
Chopsticks upright are a bad omen.
因为这像是在给死人上香
It resembles incense at a funeral.
万事皆有含义
Nothing is without meaning.
那么你跑出房间的那晚
So, the other night at the house,
你跑进雨里
when you ran out in the rain
又是什么含义
what did that mean?
当时爷爷快死了
My grandfather was dying.
你早知道他会死
You knew he was gonna die.
他已经病了很久了
He'd been sick for a long time.
我害怕的不是他的死亡
It wasn't his death I feared.
那是什么
So, what, then?
那晚他对你说什么了
What did he tell you that night?
真理子 你父亲为什么打你
Mariko, why did your father hit you?
我试图提醒他
I was trying to warn him.
提醒什么
About what?
你爷爷对你说什么了
What did your grandfather tell you?
他跟我说
He told me that
三天后 当人们看到他的遗嘱时
in three days, when they read his will
我将会成为全日本最有权势的人
I will become the most powerful person in Japan.
他把遗产都留给了我
He gave it all to me.
整个公司吗
The company?
我不想要
I didn't want it.
他也知道
He knew that.
我不明白他为什么要给我
I don't understand why he gave it to me.
那是我父亲梦寐以求的
It was all my father dreamed of.
或许这就是原因
Well, that's why.
你的未婚夫呢 那个"森特郎"
What about this fiance of yours? Nostromo.
是森信郎
Noburo.
他知道这事吗
Does he know about this?
不知道
No.
你为什么要嫁给他
Why are you marrying him?
他看起来像个混蛋
He seems like kind of an asshole.
我爸爸去年安排好的
My father arranged it last year.
- 什么 - 这对他的仕途有帮助
- What? - It gives him a better access to the political theater.
违逆父命会令他蒙羞
To disobey my father would be to dishonor him.
我不指望你能理解
I don't expect you to understand.
你又不是日本人
You're not Japanese.
还没找到我女儿吗
まだ娘を見つけられんのか
我们的岛形状狭长
この細長い島国には
只有上下两个方向的路线跟铁路
道も線路も登りと下りしかないというのに
你们到底在干什么
何をやってるんだ
信玄大人 请您放心
信玄様　ご安心ください
我的手下已经尽全力在找了
私の部下が総力をあげて取り組んでおります
他们都是一群废物
こいつらは相当な愚か者だな
你浪费了我太多时间
わしの時間を無駄にしよって
我还要处理父亲的事务
父のことで色々忙しんだ
还不去找人
探しに行かんのか
遵命
はい
请告诉我 你的线人有好消息
Tell me you have more promising news from your contacts.
他们会在三天后宣读遗嘱
They open the will in three days.
我们快没时间了
We are running out of time.
有望很快解决
Soon, I hope.
我正派人去南部
I'm sending men to the South.
那是我们发现尸体的地方
That's where we found the bodies.
如果山口组闯入葬礼
葬儀にヤクザが紛れたことは
说明有内鬼接应
内に通してるものがいるってことでしょ
放心 他们绝对不会发现我在这里
大丈夫　ここなら絶対に見つからないから
太危险了
危険だよ
我现在就去找你
今すぐそっちに行くから
不行 他们会跟着你的
ダメよ　付けられるわ
你不用担心我
心配しないで
拜托你
お願い
再给我几天时间
あと数日間だけ頂戴
我没事的
私なら大丈夫
罗根也在这里
ローガンもいるし
但是他不是受伤了吗
彼ケガしてるじゃない
真理子
真理子ちゃん
有人来了
誰か来た
真理子
Mariko?
- 我得挂了 - 喂
- 行かなきゃ　- もしもし?
真理子
Mariko?
- 真理子 - 婆婆 怎么了
- 真理子ちゃん?　- どうしたの?　おばあちゃん
真理子 有棵大树倒在路上了
真理子ちゃん　道路に大きな木が倒れてさ
那些小伙子想把它搬开 但那棵树动都不动
若い人がどけようとしとったけど　なかなかどけられんくてよ
叔叔 请喝茶
おとうさん　お茶入ります
辛苦您了 小心烫
お疲れ様です　熱いで気を付けてください
你还好吗
Are you okay?
有点累
Tired.
你需要什么吗
Do you need something?
不
No.
- 您好 - 您好
- こんにちは　- こんにちは
- 有苹果吗 - 苹果吗 给你 谢谢
- リンゴもあるかな　- リンゴ?　な　ありがとう
这个对你有好处
This will help.
是时候了
It's time.
怎么
What?
拜托 收下它
Please. Take it.
谢谢你
Thank you.
不对
No.
用两只手
Two hands.
日本刀需要双手握
Japanese sword require two hands.
- 像这样吗 - 是的
- Like that? - That's it.
真漂亮 矢志田
It's beautiful, Yashida.
但我不能收下
But I can't take it.
拜托
Please.
谢谢
Thank you.
好好保管
Keep it safe.
替我好好保管
Keep it safe for me.
总有一天我会来取的
Someday, I'll come get it.
是时候了
It's time.
当时我就在这里
I was here when it happened.
这是我遇到你爷爷的地方
It's how I met your grandfather.
我们藏在那儿
We hid in there.
我听过这个故事
I heard the stories.
我的爷爷说
My grandfather would say
这里发生的一切证明
what happened here was proof
世间万物都会归于平静
that everything in the world finds peace.
最终会的
Eventually.
人遇到任何事 都可以恢复如初
That man can recover from anything.
或许你也能
Maybe you, too.
你睡得很不安稳
You don't sleep very well.
总在半夜大声叫喊
You call out in the night.
琴是谁
Who's Jean?
我们该回去了 要下雨了
We should go back. There's rain coming.
我来泡茶
I'll make tea.
给你的
For you.
这样不对
This isn't right.
你应该打成武士结
You need this tied like a proper samurai.
你的爷爷称我为浪人
Your grandfather called me a ronin.
无主的武士
A samurai without a master.
他说我将注定永生
He said I was destined to live forever...
但却没有活下去的理由
with no reason to live.
他说的对吗
Was he right?
是的
Yes.
依然如此吗
Still?
你在做什么
What are you doing?
这样不会有好结果的
This isn't going to end well.
你爱的每一个人都会死
Everyone you love dies.
狼獾
Kuzuri.
你知道这个词是什么意思吗
Do you know what that means?
一种动物
An animal.
一种有长爪和锋利牙齿的凶猛动物
A fierce creature with long claws and sharp teeth.
它无畏无惧
It fears nothing.
我小的时候 常被噩梦惊醒
When I was a girl, I had nightmares.
然后跑去找爸爸妈妈
I'd wake up and run to my parents.
我爸爸会发怒
My father would get angry.
"回去睡觉 直面你的恐惧"
"Go back to sleep. Face your fears."
我爷爷则不一样
My grandfather was different.
他会跟我说他的朋友狼獾的故事
He told me stories about Kuzuri, his friend.
他是在井底遇到的他
Who he met at the bottom of a well.
他说 狼獾有魔力 救了他的命
He said the Kuzuri was magical and saved his life.
他还说 狼獾也会在我睡觉的时候保护我
He said Kuzuri would protect me, too, as I slept in my bed.
琴是谁
Who's Jean?
她和你一样吗
Is she like you?
她怎么了
What happened to her?
她死了
She died.
是我杀了她
I killed her.
连同狼獾也一起死了
Along with the Kuzuri.
罗根
Logan.
真理子
Mariko?
快走
行け
罗根
Logan!
真理子
Mariko?
Mariko!
不 罗根
No! Logan!
不要
No!
罗根
Logan!
不
No!
真理子
Mariko!
罗根
Logan!
不
No!
罗根
Logan!
真理子 真理子
Mariko! Mariko!
罗根
Logan!
他们要带她去哪里
Where are they taking her?
去哪里 你个人渣
Where, you piece of shit?
我不会说的 外国佬
I no talk, gaijin.
我永远都不会说的
I never talk.
谁雇的你
Who hired you?
带我去见森信郎
Take me to Noburo.
- 罗根 - 带我去找他
- Logan? - Take me to him.
我需要告诉你一些事情
I need to tell you something.
带我去 立刻
Do it. Now.
你在车里等着
You wait in the car.
- 罗根 - 怎么
- Logan. - What?
我预见到你的死亡
I saw you die.
什么
What?
我预见到你死亡了
I saw you die.
什么时候 刚刚吗
When? Just now?
不久之前
A while ago.
但我看到的幻象并不完整
But it's not like I get a complete picture.
更像是管中窥豹
More like looking through a keyhole.
但我向来都是对的
But I'm always right.
我所能预见的只是人们一生的一部分
All I can see is one part of a person's life...
他们的死亡
their death.
我看到了你的死亡
And I saw yours.
你到底看到了什么
So, what did you see?
我看到你躺着 到处都是血
I see you on your back. There's blood everywhere.
你手里握着自己的心脏
You're holding your own heart in your hand.
它不再跳动
It's not beating.
我没时间听这些废话
I don't have time for this shit.
我5岁时 就知道我的父母会怎样死去
When I was five, I knew how my own parents would die.
然后我在后座目睹了它的发生
Then I watched it happen from the back seat.
看着我
Look at me.
很多人都曾尝试杀我 可是我还活着
A lot of people have tried to kill me, and I'm still here.
是啊
Yeah,
但你现在不一样了 不是吗
but you're different now, aren't you?
他们能伤害到你
They can hurt you.
他们能杀掉你
They can kill you.
好好在车里等着
Just wait in the car.
- 我叫你在车里等着 - 你需要后援
- I said, wait in the car. - You need backup.
以你现在的情况 你并不安全
You're not safe, not in your condition.
把我当成你的保镖就好
Just think of me as your bodyguard.
真性感
Sexy.
- 来吧 - 马上就来
- Come on! - I'm coming.
等一下嘛
ちょっと待ってね
第四轮 现在开始
Okay, round four. Here we go.
这屁股真性感
いいお尻だね
出去
Get out.
没说你
Not you.
算我是老古董
Call me old-fashioned...
但我以为订婚以后
but I thought being engaged
就意味着不能再这么乱搞了
meant you were done with this kind of bullshit.
我是司法部长
I am the Minister of Justice.
你知道我能把你怎么样吗
Do you have any idea what I could do to you?
不是吧你 你竟然打算穿着你的小红内裤
Really? You're gonna try and talk tough,
站在那里 对我放狠话吗
standing there in your red underwear?
你可以用十个词
You have ten words...
十个词
ten words...
对我解释清楚 为什么 你 一个司法部长
to explain to me why you, the Minister of Justice...
会希望你的未婚妻被山口组杀死
would want your fiance killed by the Yakuza.
如果我不满意你的答案
And if I don't like what you say,
就把你从这窗户丢出去摔死
you are going through that fucking window.
你完全不了解现在的情况
You don't have the faintest idea what's going on.
- 他这句话几个词了 - 九个
- How many words was that? - Nine.
九个 只剩一个词了
Nine. You have one word left.
不是吧你
Really?
是信玄 是信玄
Shingen. Shingen!
接着说
Keep going.
他生病以后
Since he got sick...
矢志田老头花了无数的钱求医
old man Yashida spent billions on doctors, healers.
在北部的实验室囤积艾德曼合金
Stockpiling adamantium at his lab in the North,
秘密尝试延长自己的生命
secretly trying to prolong his life.
他害公司到了破产的边缘
He brought the company to the edge of bankruptcy.
他执迷于你的永生
He was obsessed with you.
那些懂事们都已经...
当部の役員たちはすでに
说英语
English!
信玄为保护那个老头撒谎了
Shingen lied, protected the old man
并向股东和董事会隐瞒了债务
concealed the debt from stockholders and the board.
他努力做个好儿子 以为会有回报
He tried to be a good son and thought he'd be rewarded.
结果老头把一切都留给了孙女
And then the old man left everything to his granddaughter.
如果真理子得到全部的权力
If Mariko got all that power,
她会一脚踹了他
she would dump his ass.
没错
It's true.
遗嘱一旦被宣读出来 真理子就...
Mariko would have never gone through with the wedding...
绝无可能举行婚礼
not once the will was revealed.
她从来都不喜欢我
She never took to me.
是吗 像你这样杰出的人
Oh, really? A class act like you.
信玄许诺我 只要我帮他 就给我一大笔钱
Shingen promised me a fortune for my help.
所以你就把枪口对准了他女儿 是吗
So, you put a hit on his daughter. Is that it?
政治生涯无法长久
Political careers don't last forever.
这话倒是真的
That's right.
等等 等等 不要
Wait! Wait! No!
你想要真相 我已经告诉你真相了
You wanted the truth. I told you the truth!
我不喜欢你的答案
I didn't like it.
快救我
助けて
你怎么知道下面有个游泳池
How did you know there's a pool down there?
我不知道
I didn't.
辛苦了
ご苦労
你知道我在大学主修的是生物吗
お前は知っていたかな　私が大学で生物学を学んだことを
遗传学
遺伝学
有些基因是隔代遗传的
遺伝子は世代を飛び越えることもある
隐性基因
劣性遺伝子
眼睛 还有头发
目や髪
天赋
才能
性格
気質
并非每个孩子都会遗传相同的特点
全ての子供が等しく受け継げるわけではない
我父亲并没有在我身上看到他自己的影子
父は私の中にではなく
而是在你身上
お前の中にこそ
看到了他自己
自分自身を見出していたのだ
你是如何说服我父亲给予你
どうやってお前がアジア最大の企業を支配できるよう
亚洲最大组织的控制权
父を説得したんだ
你疯了
狂ってるわ
非也 是我终于醒悟了
いや　やっと目覚めたんだ
如果杀了我 你会失去
私を殺せば　お父様の
仅存的一点荣誉
僅かな見栄も全て失われるのよ
别这样
やめて
不要担心 真理子
心配するな真理子
我不想伤害你 我想保护你
私はお前を傷つけるどころが守ってやりたいのだ
- 我来终结你的苦痛 - 放开我
- 痛みを止めてやる　- 放して
我来帮你实现你的愿望吧
お前の望みを叶えてやろう
帮你完成那天被那个怪物阻止的事
あの日　化け物に邪魔されてできなかったことが
我并不想死 爸爸
私が死にたかったわけじゃない
放开我
放してよ
没事了 真理子
大丈夫だ　真理子
- 跟我来 - 怎么回事
- 一緒に来い　- どういうこと?
你是无法想象的
お前には想像もつかないことさ
是你
You.
是我
Me.
很抱歉打扰 但我需要你女儿活着
Sorry to interrupt, but I need your daughter alive.
你到底是什么东西
What are you?
化学家 虚无主义者
A chemist, a nihilist...
资本家 基因突变者
a capitalist, a mutation.
蝰蛇
A viper.
保安在哪里
Where is the security?
山口组
Yakuza.
信玄
Shingen?
罗根
Logan.
(来救她)
这里 这个地方
This. This here.
这是哪里
Where is this?
矢志田大人出生的地方
Master Yashida's birthplace.
公司在山腰建立了一个机构
The company built a facility into the mountainside.
有多远
How far?
离这里500公里
500 kilometers from here.
我要把它从体内取出来
I gotta get that thing out of me.
怎么做
How?
不 停下 罗根
No, stop, Logan.
我预见了你的死亡 我从没错过
I saw you die. I'm never wrong.
我从来都没错过
I'm never wrong.
你不是每次都是对的
You're not always right.
你就没预见到那个老头的死
You didn't know the old man was gonna bite it.
我看到你死在像这样的屋子里 心脏握在手里...
I saw you die in a room like this with your heart in your hand.
我不能让她在那群疯子和杀人狂手里 雪生
I can't leave her with those freaks and killers, Yukio.
我是她获救的唯一机会
I'm the only chance she's got,
但我得先把那东西弄出来
but not with that thing inside me.
你会死的 罗根
You're going to die, Logan.
或许那也没什么
Maybe that's okay.
不 听我说 罗根
No, listen to me, Logan!
不要 快住手 罗根
No, stop. Logan!
接下去你还是不要看的好
You're not gonna want to watch this part.
不要 住手 快住手 求你了
No! Listen to me! Please, no!
不要 快住手
No, stop. Listen to me.
罗根
Logan!
滚开
Move!
你离他远点
Stay away from him.
他害死了你的主人
He killed your master.
染指你的姐姐
Put hands on your sister.
现在你竟然想要他吗
And now you want him?
不好 我看不见那东西了
Oh, no. I can't see.
你永远都不过是个要饭的
You'll always be a beggar.
你疯了
You're crazy.
不
No!
雪生
Yukio.
罗根
Logan!
罗根 罗根
Logan! Logan!
罗根
Logan!
不准伤害我的朋友
Don't hit my friends.
真理子在哪里
Where's Mariko?
她不在了 蝰蛇那个贱人把她带走了
She's gone. That Viper bitch took her.
都怪我父亲对基因突变的痴迷
It was my father's obsession with mutation,
那不过是上帝的失误
with God's mistakes
比如你和她
like you and her,
那毁了我们整个家族
that ruined this house.
你试图对自己的亲生女儿下毒手
You tried to kill your daughter.
带着这份愧疚活着吧
Live with that.
你究竟是什么怪物
What kind of monster are you?
我是金刚狼
The Wolverine.
小心 慢慢起来
Hey, come here, come here. That's it.
我错了
I was wrong.
我就说吧
I told you.
让我看看你的伤
Let me have a look at you.
我没事的
It's nothing.
谢谢你
Thank you.
这是个陷阱 罗根
It's a trap, Logan.
这到底是什么地方
なんなのよここは
你究竟对我隐瞒了什么
何を隠してるの?
你马上就能知道了 真理子
すぐわかるさ　真理子
欢迎啊 真理子
Welcome, Mariko.
别怕 真理子 她也是为矢志田家效力的
It's all right, Mariko. She also serves the House of Yashida.
她只为自己效力吧
She serves herself.
她对罗根下手了
She infected Logan.
还有我爷爷
And what about Grandfather?
你对他使用了什么致命手段
What did you infect him with?
我只是实现他的遗愿
I granted his dying wish.
让他安息
I helped him rest.
现在 轮到你了
Now, it's your turn.
过来帮忙
手を貸せ
给我听好 变种人 不准伤害她
Listen to me, mutant. She will not be harmed.
她不会有事的
She will be fine.
前提是你把你的事做好
So long as you do your job.
罗根很快就会到 我们要做好准备
Logan will be here soon, we should prepare.
引他过来是一回事
It was easy to lure him here.
要抓住他可没那么简单
It's another thing to capture him.
我们准备好了 他没见识过黑衣族的厉害
We're ready. He's never faced the Black Clan.
是没错 但...
Yes, well...
给你的箭头蘸上这个
Dip your arrows in this.
这不会杀死他
It won't kill him,
但能让他动作变慢
but it will slow him down.
不需要你的毒液
Keep your potions.
他现在很弱 根本不是我们的对手
He's no challenge for us now. He's weak.
好吧
Okay.
不过如果你失败了
But when you fail,
还可以继续用
you have this.
休息得怎么样
Did you have a nice rest?
我不知道你究竟用了什么卑鄙手段
I don't know what you said or did
欺骗了原田和爷爷 但是...
to deceive Harada or my grandfather...
别激动
Now, now, calm down.
是你爷爷先找上我的
Your grandfather sought me out.
现在我是这个家族的继承人
I am the head of this family now.
你知道为什么选你吗
And why do you suppose that is?
为什么那个老头子会选择你作为继承人
Why do you think the old man chose you?
是因为觉得你够强大吗
Because you are strong?
还是因为你够软弱
Or because you are weak?
我知道你是来大战一场的
I see you've come to fight.
但这毫无意义
It's pointless.
你很虚弱 而且寡不敌众
You're weak. You're outnumbered.
黑衣族世代保护矢志田家族已经有七百年
The Black Clan has protected the House of Yashida for 700 years.
你就带了这么点人吗
Is that all the men you brought?
我要去救她
I'm gonna get her.
我们非常感谢你之前对真理子的保护
We are grateful for your protection of Mariko.
但是为了她的家族 你还需要做一个牺牲
But there is one more sacrifice you must make for her family.
滚蛋去吧 小帅哥
Go fuck yourself, pretty boy.
动手
やれ
都给我上
マーキネス　行くぞ
上
行け
雪生 快跑
Yukio, run!
罗根
Logan.
凯拉
Kayla.
我爱你 凯拉
I love you. Kayla!
罗根
Logan.
真理子
Mariko!
琴
Jean.
救救我
Save me.
退下 没必要
Stand back. There is no need.
她在哪儿 真理子在哪儿
Where is she? Where's Mariko?
她在哪儿
Where is she?
真理子在哪儿
"Where is Mariko?"
还在为她伤心呢
Still pining away?
真感人
That's so sweet.
叹为观止吧
Impressive, no?
他也是用艾德曼合金制成的 跟你一样
He is made of Adamantium, just like you.
罗根 我能体会你的心情 你很沮丧
Oh, Logan, you know what, I get it. You're frustrated.
我知道她在这儿 我要见她
I know she's here. I want to see her.
你想知道答案
You want answers.
没错 我想要答案
Yes, I want answers!
抱歉了 我也想告诉你答案
I'm sorry, I wish I could say more,
但人家就是看中我嘴巴牢才雇的我
but I was hired in part for my discretion.
我相信也是
I'm sure you were.
此外
That
我还有把生物化学与形而上学结合起来的才能
and a certain talent for combining biochemistry and metaphysics.
剧毒是我的专长
High-grade toxins are my specialty.
对人类已知的全部毒素天生免疫 还挺有用的
It helps to be genetically immune to every poison known to man, as I am.
我甚至对人类自身的各种缺陷都免疫
And immune to the toxin that is man himself, as I am.
我告诉你 你这个扭曲的变种贱人
I'll tell you what, you twisted mutant bitch,
不如现在就打开手铐
why don't you open these bracelets
我们比比看究竟谁更强大
and we'll see who's made of what?
秀爪子啦 那我们开始吧
The claws. Now we can begin.
我知道你对他有感情
お前はあいつに思いを寄せてるのは知ってる
但你必须忘了他
でも忘れる
你是矢志田家的人
お前は矢志田家の人間なんだ
那个女人背叛了爷爷
あの女はお爺様を裏切ったのよ
你也一样吧
あなたもそうってことでしょ?
你错了 真理子
違う　真理子
我们从小一起长大的
俺たちは幼馴染だろう?
你要相信我
俺を信じてくれ
你让开 我要去下面
そこをどいて　下に行かなきゃ
他没对你做过任何事吧
彼はあなたに何もしてないじゃない?
他救了我的命啊
私の命を救ってくれたのよ
忘了他吧 真理子
あいつを忘れろ　真理子
我也不愿意这样做
俺も辛いんだ
我是在按照你爷爷的计划行事
でも俺は　お前のお爺さんの計画に従う
你心脏上的那只虫子是我放进去的
The suppressant bug you found inside of you was mine.
你竟然亲手把它取出来了
You took it out on your own.
我还真没料到这一出
I didn't see that coming.
蝰蛇是个危险的人
ワイバーが危険なのは
我很清楚
俺も知ってる
但她只不过是为了完成你爷爷愿望的一枚棋子
でもあいつは　お前のお爺さんの願いを叶えるまでの駒だ
她在哪儿
Where is she?
别担心
心配するな
你很强大
You are strong.
你充满勇气
You have courage.
真正的勇气
Real courage.
但现在勇气也帮不了你多少了
But that won't help much now.
什么鬼...
What the...
你要相信我
俺を信じてくれ
相信我很难吗
難しいことか
我们命中注定要在一起
俺たちもっと強い絆で結ばれてんだ
现在也是一样吧
今でもそうだろう
也许吧
そうよね
住手
Stop!
这太疯狂了
マジか
快走
Let's go.
跑
Go!
快跑
Run!
快走
Come on.
- 真理子 快走 - 快跑
- Mariko, come! - Go! Run!
真理子 快出去
Mariko, get out!
住手
止めろ
来啊
Come on.
这样是不对的
This is not the way.
两手握刀
Two hands.
主人
Master.
嘿 大块头
Hey! Bub!
原田
Harada.
对不起
ごめんなさい
去死吧
Now, you die.
今天不是我的死期
Today is not my day.
罗根先生
Logan-san.
不用这么惊讶
Don't look so shocked.
在长崎时 多亏有你 我才躲过一劫
With you at my side, I survived Nagasaki.
显然 这次我依然能挺过去
Surely, I could survive this.
没事的 很快就好
It's all right. It won't take long.
格林医生和我都在等待这一刻
Dr. Green and I have been waiting.
现在全靠这身盔甲维持着我的性命
It's only this armor that's kept me alive.
我们造了这个东西让我变得强壮
We built it to make me strong,
那样我就能夺取你不愿意给我的东西
so I can take what you would not give.
把你不想要的自愈能力
And transfer your unwanted healing
转移到我身上
to my body.
我的千秋家业必须被保护好
My legacy must be preserved.
你的错误就在于相信
Your mistake was to believe
无止尽的生命是没有意义的
that a life without end can have no meaning.
只有无止尽的生命才有意义
It is the only life that can.
再坚持下
Hold on.
就快好了了
We are almost there.
你一直祈求的平静
The peace, the peace you've wanted.
这是你的奖励
Your reward.
我这可是赐予了你 你一直期盼的死亡啊
You know, I'm giving you the very death you longed for.
这种感觉
This feeling,
成为无敌的存在
to be invincible
就跟你一样
like you.
你才是真正的怪物
本物の化け物はあなたよ
真理子
Mariko.
是我啊 是爷爷啊
It's me. Your grandfather.
我爷爷已经入土了
I buried my grandfather.
你不是请我来跟你告别的吗
You asked me to come say goodbye.
永别了
Sayonara.
你们没事吧
Are you all right?
罗根
Logan.
你来了
You're here.
当然了
Of course.
你能留下吗
Can you stay?
我不能
I can't.
你可以的
Yes, you can.
这是你一直想要的
This is what you wanted.
不再是了
Not anymore.
我一个人在这里很孤单
I'm all alone here.
是你将我置于此地的
You put me here.
你当时伤害了别人 琴
You were hurting people, Jean.
我不得不那么做
I had to.
我爱你 琴
I love you, Jean.
我会永远爱你
I always will.
我会很寂寞的
寂しくなるわ
你是我唯一的家人了
たっだ一人の家族なんだから
保重 姐姐
元気でね　お姉ちゃん
认为你还会来看我 是不是错了
Am I wrong to think you might visit me soon?
留下来
Stay.
我不能 公主殿下
I can't, princess.
我是个战士
I'm a soldier,
我已经逃避自己的职责太久了
and I've been hiding too long.
今日财经人物采访 真理子·矢志田
In our business profile tonight, Mariko Yashida.
矢志田家族继承大权移交第三代
A two-generation passing of the torch in the Yashida family
科技巨头创始人之孙女真理子·矢志田
as Mariko Yashida takes the helm from her grandfather,
将从爷爷手中接过整个家族事业
who built this tech giant.
我明白对任何一个公司来说
I know it will always be the purpose
赚钱永远是个目标
for a corporation to make a profit,
但是矢志田工业相信
but Yashida Industries believes
我们同时也能服务整个社会
we can also work with our community.
你决定好了吗
So, have you decided?
决定什么
What?
真理子说我们可以想去哪就去哪
Mariko says we can go wherever we want.
只要说个地方
Just say where.
你干什么
What are you doing?
我是你的保镖呀
I'm your bodyguard.
你想去哪里
So, where do you want to go?
先起飞再说
Let's just start with up.
然后呢
And then?
再说吧
We'll see.
有意思
Interesting.
《金刚狼2》
(两年后)
我们拥有最尖端的科技
With cutting edge technology,
以及最具智慧的科技人才
and the world's leading minds,
我们站在世界的前沿
we are on the frontlines,
保障您的身心健康和人身安全
keeping you healthy, keeping you safe.
特拉斯克工业
Trask Industries.
今日解决明日忧
Solving tomorrow's problems, today.
我选择搜身安检
I'll take the pat-down.
退出机器安检
Opt out.
您可以过了 先生
You can go ahead, sir.
我再等等
I'll wait.
你要干什么
What do you want?
黑暗势力在蠢蠢欲动 金刚狼
There are dark forces, Wolverine.
人类正在建造某种武器
Human forces building a weapon
可能会给变种人带来灭顶之灾
that could bring about the end of our kind.
你问我要干什么 我需要你的援助
What do I want? I want your help.
我凭什么相信你
Why would I trust you?
你自然不会信
You wouldn't.
你好 罗根
Hello, Logan.
这怎么可能
How is this possible?
正如我很久之前告诉过你的
As I told you a long time ago,
有天赋的人 不止你一个
you are not the only one with gifts.